原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     一只虾   辛巴   嘟嘟矢   24_1900
校对     木浅
时间轴     一口一颗冬枣  一查香蕉  一夏葡萄
时间轴     一半小鱼干  一啾啾蜂蜜  小式
后期     8T
总监     somehacker  木浅
十五年前  一场科学实验出错  导致一群高智商猩猩崛起
人类却因为猿流感病毒濒临灭绝
崛起
以凯撒为首的新猿族建立伊始  幸存的人类力求和平共处
而叛徒科巴给人类带来了一场报复性袭击  和平已逝  人猿大战一触即发
黎明
幸存之人向北部军事基地[仅存的美国国军聚集地]发出紧急求助
另一边冷血的特种部队上校带着他的精英部队执行消灭猩猩的任务
猿族逃亡了近两年  现传闻凯撒在树林深处的秘密基地里筹备着大战
战争日益激烈
战争
猩球崛起3  终极之战
猩猩杀手
君子红颜[以教黑猩猩说话的真实案例改编的电影]
濒危物种
队长
Captain!
蠢驴
那是战壕吗
Is that a trench?
好像里面还有更多猩猩
It looks like there's more of them inside.
2-6号呼叫指挥
Echo 2-6 to command.
上校  北边的树林发现三只猩猩
Colonel, we've got eyes on three Kong in the north woods.
一只有武器  蠢驴刚发现另一个战壕
One of them is armed. And our donkey just spotted another trench.
基地可能就在附近
Maybe the base is near.
收到  长官
Yes, sir.
是  长官  收到  完毕
Yes, sir, copy. Over.
蠢驴过来
Hey, donkey.
普里彻
Preacher.
那个带枪的
The one with the gun.
它一倒下  你们就向战壕进攻
As soon as the gunner's down, you guys take out the trench.
-收到  长官  -收到  长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
开火
Fire!
给我上
Come on!
换弹夹
Reload!
撤退  撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
上校  听到吗  上校
Colonel, do you copy? Colonel!
你是谁
Who is this?
普里彻  长官  我是普里彻
Preacher, sir! It's Preacher!
你在哪  士兵  我要你的具体位置
Where are you, soldier? I need your position.
-我也不知道  -你四周有什么
- I don't know! -  What do you see?
长官  我什么都看不见
I can't see anything, sir.
我们伤亡惨重  队长也死了  长官
We lost a lot of men, and the captain is dead, sir.
先冷静下来  现在由你来指挥
Okay, calm down. You're in command now.
指挥吗  长官
Command, sir?
我感觉只剩我一个了
I think it's just me all by myself now.
控制好局面
Take control.
上校  我不行啊  长官
Colonel, I don't think I'm gonna make it, sir.
对不起
I'm sorry.
很对不起  长官
I'm so sorry, sir.
听我说  杀一个算一个
Listen to me. You kill as many as you can.
不  不  不
No! No, no!
63名阵亡
Sixty-three dead.
是你
You're him.
你是凯撒
You're Caesar.
我们找了你很久
We've been searching for you for so long.
据说你有个秘密指挥基地
We heard you had a hidden command base.
但我们找不到
But we could never find it.
有人开始猜测你已经死了
Some of us started to think that you might be dead.
但麦卡洛上校说你肯定藏在什么地方
But Colonel McCullough said you were out here somewhere.
-杀了我们吧  -闭嘴  老兄
- Just kill us already. - Shut up, man!
什么  他们是畜生
What? They're animals.
反正他也会杀死我们
He's gonna slaughter us.
挑起这场战争的不是我
I did not start this war.
罪魁祸首已经死了
The ape who did is dead.
他叫科巴
His name was Koba.
我杀死了他
I killed him.
现在  我战斗仅仅是为了
Now, I fight only...
保护猿族
to protect apes.
是吗
Yeah?
那他呢
What about him?
我们那有十多个像他这样的猩猩
We've got 10 more just like him.
我知道他们
I know these apes.
他们是科巴的手下
They follow Koba.
他们之前想杀我
They tried to kill me.
他们怕我报复他们
They fear what I will do to them.
所以现在  他们就归顺了你们
So now, they serve you.
不过是为了活命
Just to survive.
我才不怕你
I don't fear you.
你才应该畏惧
You must fear.
你觉得森林还能保护你们多久
How long you think woods can protect you?
人类不会放过你们的
Humans destroy you.
他们的老大无所不能
Their Kerna has all power.
对他们来说  他如神一般
For them, he more than just human.
他就是主宰
He everything.
他说过  先杀凯撒
He said, first Caesar die...
接着所有都得死
then all of you die.
温特  把这叛徒带出去
Winter! Take this traitor outside!
他们怎么处置
What should we do with the humans?
你要放了我们
You're letting us go?
告诉你们上校  你们已经见过我了
Tell your Colonel you have seen me now...
传话给他
and I have a message for him.
不再涉足森林  战火就能停息
Leave us the woods, and the killing can stop.
你觉得他们会将这信息传达给上校吗
Do you think they will give him the message?
他们活着回去就是我的信息  莫里斯
They are the message, Maurice.
就能让他知道我们并不野蛮
He will see we are not savages.
那叛徒袭击了我  然后逃跑了
The traitor attacked me! He got away!
科巴...
Koba...
依然困扰着我们
still haunts us.
为什么当初我没看到
Why didn't I see...
他肯定无法原谅人类对他的所作所为
that he could not forgive what humans did to him?
谁都不知道他的内心...
No one could have known how much darkness...
有多么阴暗
...was living inside him.
父亲
Father...!
欢迎回家  火箭
Welcome home, Rocket.
挺累吧
You look tired.
长途跋涉啊
It was a long journey.
父亲  我们有新发现
Father, we found something!
来
Come.
母亲
Mother...!
科尼利厄斯
Cornelius...
快叫哥哥
Say hi to your brother!
儿子  看看谁在那儿
Look who's here, son...
蕾克
Lake...
机会来了  父亲
This is it, father...
我们可以重来  建立一个新家
We can start over... A new home.
这些山的背后是什么  儿子
What is beyond those mountains, son?
给他们看看  火箭
Show them, Rocket...
是沙漠
A desert!
旅途很遥远
The journey is long...
不过这样人类才找不到我们
But that is why humans will not find us.
我们今晚就要启程
We must leave tonight!
今晚  怎么可能
Tonight? That's impossible!
我们还有多少时间  蕾克
How long can we wait, Lake?
士兵已经逼近
Soldiers getting closer!
温特...
Winter...
你儿子离开了那么久  凯撒
Your son's been gone, Caesar...
他不知道我们有多艰难
He doesn't know how hard it's been.
我知道你很害怕
I know you are scared...
我们都怕
We all are...
但我们要从长计议
But we are still planning...
没错
Yes.
我们要找到离开树林的万全之策
We must find a safe way out of the woods.
之前只有你们两个  数量少
There were only two of you.
但现在我们是...一族人
But we are... many.
我们一定能找到出去的路
We will find a way out of here.
猿族团结...
Apes together...
则强
strong.
留在这里  儿子
Stay here, son!
保护好你的母亲和弟弟
Protect your mother and brother!
凯撒  出什么事了
Caesar! What's wrong?!
有多少兄弟在巡逻
How many on patrol?
五六个吧
Five? Six?
去找他们
Get them!
卢卡  把火箭也叫上
Luca, get Rocket, too.
利马4号呼叫指挥  上校  你...
Lima four to command. Colonel, did you...
火箭
Rocket!
怎么了
What happened?
我听到他说话  上校来了
I heard him talking! The Colonel is here!
99  已获取目标
99, target acquired.
99  已获取目标  重复  凯撒已死
99, target acquired. Repeat. King Kong is dead.
走吧  我可以从这里离开
Let's go. I can get out from here.
凯撒
Caesar...
我们找不到温特
We can't find Winter!
他之前那么害怕  我想他背叛了我们
He was scared! I think he betrayed us!
找到科尼利厄斯没
Have you found Cornelius yet?
还在找
We're still searching.
我们去找凯撒的小儿子
Let's go look for Caesar's little son.
科尼利厄斯
Cornelius!
没事了
You're safe now.
蕾克
Lake...
你爱过我儿子
You loved my son.
在我回来前照顾好他弟弟
Look after his brother until I return.
你不跟我们一起去新的家园吗
You're not coming with us to our new home?
不
No.
跟着蕾克
Go with Lake.
凯撒
Caesar!
你追不到他们的
You're not going after them?!
不是他们  是他
Not them. Him.
凯撒  你是我们的领袖
Caesar, you are our leader!
我们可不能没有你的带领
We can't leave without you!
必须这样
You must.
士兵很快就会回来
The soldiers will be back soon.
爸爸
Father!
等我找到他
When I find him...
士兵们就会来追杀我
the soldiers will all come after me.
这可能是你们离开森林的最佳时机
That may give you the best chance to get out of the woods.
他要去哪
Where is he going?!
凯撒  凯撒
Caesar! Caesar!
他们的军营经常变换位置
The soldiers' camp is always moving.
我的那些守卫知道他们在哪
My guards think they know where it is.
让我带你去
Let me take you.
你需要我的支援
You need me to back you up!
不
No.
拜托
Please...
我知道失去儿子...
I know what it's like...
是怎样的滋味
...to lose a son.
我可能回不来
I may not make it back.
所以我才要跟着你
That's why I'm coming.
确保你能平安归来
To make sure you do.
守卫们认为士兵会在这里
Guards think soldiers here...
经常有炊烟升起
Always fires burning.
这里没有人...
No one here...
四下搜索
Search the area.
我只是要把它们放下
I'm just gonna put this down.
他一个人在这里干什么
What's he doing out here alone?
说不定他是个逃兵
Maybe he's a deserter?
四处看看
Look around.
有用的都带走
Take what you can.
她有点不对劲儿
Something wrong with her.
我觉得她不会说话
I don't think she can speak.
走吧
Come.
她一个人会死的
She'll die out here alone.
我们不能带着她  莫里斯
We cannot take her, Maurice.
我知道
I understand...
可是我不能把她扔下
But I cannot leave her.
你找到上校了吗
Did you find the Colonel?
没有
No.
温特
Winter.
上校在哪儿
Where's the Colonel?
他走了
He's gone.
走了?
Gone?
他今天早上就离开了
He left this morning...
还带了许多人和他一起
...took many men with him.
北方会来更多士兵
More soldiers are coming down from the North.
上校去边界和他们
The Colonel is going to meet them...
会合了
...at the border.
什么边界  为什么
What border? Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
其余的人明天出发
But the rest of us are going tomorrow.
那些蠢驴们认为从北方来的士兵们
The donkeys think the soldiers from the North...
是来帮助他们永远解决掉黑猩猩的
...are coming to help finish off the apes for good.
那天  在山上那场战役结束后
That day, after the battle on the hill...
我们抓住的那个蠢驴
The donkey we caught
向我保证  只要我交代你们的藏身之处
promised me the Colonel would spare my life...
上校就会饶我一命
If I told them where you were hiding.
原谅我
Forgive me!
我的儿子
My son...
我的妻子
my wife...
都死了
are dead.
我们现在该怎么办
Now what do we do?
等这些士兵们开拔
Wait till the soldiers go...
跟着他们找到上校
Follow them to the Colonel.
科巴
Koba!
猿族
Ape...
不能自相残杀
not kill ape.
士兵们要出发了
The soldiers are leaving!
他们停下来了
They stopped.
下马
Get down!
他们在朝什么开枪
What are they shooting at?
不知道
I don't know.
他们为什么要杀你
Why did they shoot you?
和她一样
Like her!
他不能说话
He cannot speak!
那些伤足够要了他的命
He will die of those wounds.
卢卡
Luca...
那些士兵去哪了
Where did the soldiers go?!
温特说他们要去一个边界
Winter said they were going to a border.
没错  可到底是哪条路
Yes, but which way is that?!
坏猩猩
Bad Ape!
Bad Ape.
你是谁
Who are you?
你在这做什么
What are you doing here?
我觉得他听不懂
I don't think he understands.
我不认识他
I don't recognize him.
他不是我们的人
He's not one of us.
这儿只有你一个吗
Are you alone here?
冷吗
Cold?
冷
Cold.
我看到了女孩  我以为你们是人类
I see girl, I think you human.
可你们是猩猩
But you ape.
和我一样
Like me.
不  放下
No, put down.
你在这儿多久了
How long have you been here?
很久了
Long time.
很久很久了
Long, long time.
家
Home.
以前的家
Old home.
动物园
你还有同伴吗
Are there more like you?
动物园里的其他黑猩猩
More apes from zoo.
死了  都死了
Dead. All dead.
很久了
Long time.
人类变得病态
Human get sick.
黑猩猩变聪明了
Ape get smart.
然后人类就开始屠杀黑猩猩
Then human kill ape.
但我没死
But not me.
我跑了
I run.
你学会了说话
You learn to speak...
听  人类
Listen. Human...
坏猩猩
"Bad Ape!"
Bad Ape.
不
No.
别碰
No touch.
这是我的
That's mine.
我没事
I'm okay!
不可思议
Amazing...
我以为只有我们是这样
Always thought we were the only ones.
世上会不会还有更多
Wonder if there are more in the world?
像我们一样的黑猩猩
More apes like us.
吃  吃
Eat! Eat.
新朋友
New friends.
特殊的日子
Special day.
加利福尼亚州边境隔离设施 塔楼
边境隔离设施
这是在哪里找到的
Where did you get this?
不好的地方
Bad place.
很久以前找到的
I find long time ago.
离开动物园  我在找食物
After zoo, I look for food...
我发现了人类动物园
I find human zoo.
病人动物园
Zoo for sick.
很多高墙
Big walls.
生病的人类往上爬
Sick human climb.
坏人类大开杀戒
Bad human kill.
然后  所有人都病了
And then, all get sick.
很久之前就死光了
All dead now for a long time.
很久很久
Long time.
坏人类?
Bad humans?
是士兵吗
Soldiers?
士兵
Soldiers.
一个废弃的军营
A deserted military camp!
在边界上
On the border!
也许上校和他的军队就是要去那里
Maybe the Colonel and the troops are going there?
那里远吗  你能带我们去吗
Is it far? Can you take us?
人类动物园?
Human zoo?
不 不 不要回去
No. No, no go back there.
都死了  我来到这里  这里很安全
Everyone dead. I come here. Very safe here.
绝不回去
Never go back.
拜托你  你一定要带我们去
Please, you must take us!
不  不  不带
No! No! Cannot take!
不能带  不  不
Cannot take. No! No!
看  看
Look! Look!
雪更大了  不能走  必须留下
More snow. Cannot go. Must stay.
你们吃  你们休息
You eat, you rest.
和我留在这儿
Stay here with me.
这个  你拿着
Here, you keep.
她拿着
She keep.
雪弗兰  诺瓦2[汽车]
这个孩子
Who is...
是谁
child?
我不知道
I don't know.
可她跟着你们
But she with you.
她没有亲人了
She has no one else.
我看见你刚才在看她
I see you look at her just now.
很伤心
Look sad.
你有孩子吗
You have child?
有一个
One.
其他的都被人类杀害了
The other was killed by human.
士兵吗
Soldier?
我
I
有过孩子
had child.
你能找到他吗
You think you will find him...
在人类动物园里
at human zoo?
和那些士兵在一起
With soldier?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许吧
Maybe.
那
Then...
也许我能带你们去
maybe I take you.
渴
Thirsty.
卢卡  走  我们靠近点
Luca, come. Let's go closer.
保护好他们
Keep them safe.
他们在做什么
What are they doing?
我不知道
I don't know.
那是什么  巡逻队吗
What's that? A patrol?
我没看到骑兵
I don't see riders.
不许动
Hold it!
我看见他们来了
I saw them coming!
至少这一次
At least this time...
我保护了你
I was able to protect you.
凯撒
Caesar...
你必须停止行动
This must stop...
现在去和其他黑猩猩们会合还不晚
It's not too late to join the other apes...
我们不能回头
We cannot turn back!
卢卡付出了自己的生命
Luca gave his life!
拜托了
Please...!
他们必须付出代价
They must pay.
现在
Now...
你听起来很像科巴
...you sound like Koba.
带着你们一起是一个错误
It was a mistake bringing you all.
这是我一个人的战斗
This is my fight.
我会独自解决
I will finish this alone.
走吧
Go.
现在就走
Now!
去找大部队会合
Join the others.
发生了什么
What happened?
他们不知道从哪儿冒出来
They came out of nowhere...
袭击了我们
Attacked us.
我以为我们死定了
We thought they would kill us all...
可是上校阻止了他们
But the Colonel stopped them!
他的眼里闪烁着疯狂
There was madness in his eyes!
他说我们死之前
He said they would use us,
还有用处
before we died!
然后他们就把我们带到这里
And they brought us all here!
利用你们?
Use you?
他们逼我们干活
They've been forcing us to work!
什么
What...
干什么活
What kind of work?
等等
Wait.
我的小儿子  他在这儿吗
My little son. Is he here?
格兰特和李
Grant and Lee...
罗伯特·爱德华·李将军在美国南北战争中
作为南方盟军司令最终败于尤利西斯·格兰特将军
威灵顿
Wellington...
英国威灵顿公爵在滑铁卢战役中击败了拿破仑
和拿破仑
and Napoleon...
卡斯特
Custer...
1876年美军卡斯特将军
败于印第安部落首领"坐牛"并战死
和坐牛
and Sitting Bull...
你可能没怎么读过书
You're probably not much of a reader.
但这是一个重要的时刻
But this is a big moment.
那时你在哪里
Where were you?
我们找到了你的族群  运气不错
We came upon your herd. We got lucky.
但我很惊讶你居然没和他们一起
But I was surprised you weren't with them.
希望你不会后悔饶了他一命
I hope you don't come to regret sparing his life.
他枪法很不错
He's quite a good shot.
你终于来救你的猩猩们了
Have you finally come to save your apes?
我是来找你的
I came for you.
找我
For me?
那晚我杀的是谁
Who did I kill that night?
我妻子
My wife.
和我儿子
My son.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我是冲你去的
I was there for you.
天哪
My God.
看看你的眼睛
Look at your eyes.
都快和人类一样了
Almost human.
你怎么知道我在这里
How did you know I was here?
有人告诉我你会来
I was told you were coming.
有更多的士兵会从北方过来
That more soldiers from the North...
来这和你会合
would be joining you here.
和我会合
Joining me?
来解决我们
To finish us off.
永远解决
For good.
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
好吧
Okay.
我们走
Let's go.
父亲
Father!
蕾克
Lake...
原谅他们吧
Forgive them.
我们受的苦够多了
We've been through much.
父亲
Father!
我都做了什么
What have I done?
全体  立定
Battalion, halt!
血
Blood!
让草生长
Makes the grass grow!
我们
We!
让血流动
Make the blood flow!
我们是开始
We are the beginning!
也是结束
And the end!
我们来这里后都没得到过食物和水
We haven't had food or water since we got here...
他们要城墙干什么
Why do they need a wall?
蠢驴
Donkey!
-带他过来  -好的  好的
- Get him. - Okay, okay, okay...
住手
Leave him!
让他们回去工作
Tell them to get back to work.
猩猩们需要食物和水
Apes need food and water.
告诉他们
Tell them.
给他们食物
Give them food...
和水
and water.
五
Five...
四
Four...
三
Three...
二
Two...
快点  回去工作
Hurry! Back to work!
把他吊起来  蠢驴
String him up, donkey.
坏地方
Bad place.
很坏的地方
Bad, bad place.
你看到了什么
What you see?
得去救他们  但怎么救
Must save them! But how?
必须想办法
Must think!
凯撒会怎么做
What would Caesar do?
不
Oh, no!
怎么看起来那么小
Why so small?
上校答应了你什么
What did the Colonel promise you?
你真的以为我们死后...
You really think he'll let you live...
他还会让你活着
after we are gone?
你还让他们叫你"蠢驴"
You let them call you "Donkey."
可你是猩猩
You are ape.
上校想见你
Colonel want see you.
历史
再敢干涉他们工作
Interfere with the work again...
我就一个一个把他们都杀了
and I'll begin slaughtering the apes one by one.
听懂了吗  我需要那堵墙
Understand? I need that wall.
猩猩们需要食物和水
Apes need food and water.
等他们完成工作就会有食物和水了
They'll get food and water when they finish their work.
给猩猩食物和水
Give apes food and water...
否则他们完不成工作
or they cannot finish.
你真是太感情用事了
You know, you are very emotional.
你凭什么以为你有权提要求
What makes you think you're in a position to make demands?
好了  我们走吧
Okay, let's go.
正往这里来的士兵
The soldiers who are coming here...
他们不是来和你会合的吧  是不是
they are not coming to join you, are they?
我看到外面墙上有人在准备战斗
I saw men outside on the wall, preparing for battle.
他们告诉我你很聪明
They told me you were smart...
但这确实厉害
but that's impressive.
不
No.
他们不是来和我会合的
They won't be joining me.
他们是来对付你的
They are against you?
他们害怕我
They fear me.
为什么
Why?
因为你杀自己人
Because you kill your own men?
我们发现了尸体
We found bodies.
他们有些...
Something wrong...
不对劲
with these men.
我的老天  你真是厉害
Jesus Christ, you are impressive.
你真是构想了一出好戏
Well, you paint quite a picture.
你该怎么看我啊
What you must think of me.
我觉得你毫无仁慈可言
I think you have no mercy.
你是来杀我的
You came here to kill me.
你打算对我仁慈了吗
Were you gonna show me mercy?
我早已对你仁慈了
I showed you mercy...
我放走了你的人
when I spared your men.
我想要和平
I offered you peace...
你却杀了我的家人
and you killed my family.
仁慈
Mercy.
你知道你的仁慈会对我们造成什么后果吗
You have any idea what your mercy would do to us?
你们比我们强大得多
You're much stronger than we are.
你还聪明得要死
You're smart as hell.
无论你怎么说  你终将取代我们
No matter what you say, you'd eventually replace us.
这是自然法则
That's the law of nature.
讽刺的是  是我们创造了你
The irony is, we created you.
我们试图与自然抗争  让它屈从于我们的意志
We tried to defy nature, bend it to our will.
从那以后自然就一直在惩罚我们的傲慢
Nature has been punishing us for our arrogance ever since.
十个月前  我派侦查小队去寻找你的基地
10 months ago, I sent out recon units to look for your base.
我自己的儿子也是其中一员
My own son was a soldier with one of the units.
有一天他突然说不出话了
One day he suddenly stopped speaking.
他退化了  变得像动物一样
He became primitive, like an animal.
他们联系我说他们觉得他疯了
They contacted me and said that they thought he'd lost his mind.
说是战争让他不堪重负
That the war was too much for him.
但接着照顾他的那个人也失声了
Then the man who cared for him stopped speaking too.
他们的医生在失声之前有个猜想
Their medic had a theory, before he stopped speaking...
认为差点灭绝了人类的那种病毒
that the virus that almost wiped us out...
幸存下来的每个人都还携带着的那种病毒
the virus that every human survivor still carries...
突变了
had suddenly changed.
变异了
Mutated.
如果扩散开来
And that if it spread...
这一次它将彻底摧毁人类
it would destroy humanity for good this time.
不是通过杀死我们
Not by killing us...
而是通过剥夺我们的人类特性
but by robbing us of those things that make us human.
我们的语言能力  思维能力
Our speech, our higher thinking...
它会将我们变成走兽
It would turn us into beasts.
你想跟我谈仁慈
You talk about mercy?
换成是你  你会怎么做
What would you have done?
那一刻我顿悟了
It was a moment of clarity for me.
我意识到
I realized...
我必须牺牲我唯一的儿子
that I would have to sacrifice my only son...
来拯救整个人类
so that humanity could be saved.
枪在我手里
I held that gun in my hand...
拿了很久
for a long time.
我瞄准了我唯一的孩子
I pointed it at my only child...
他看着我
he looked at me...
双眼充满信任
trust in his eyes.
即使在他那退化的眼神中
Even in his primitive gaze...
我还是感受到了他的...爱
I felt his... love.
我扣下了扳机
I pulled the trigger.
那净化了我
It purified me.
让我明确了目标
It made my purpose clear.
我下令杀了其他被感染的人  所有人
I gave the orders to kill the other infected. All of them.
烧掉他们的东西
Burn their belongings...
和任何可能传播病毒的东西
and anything that might spread contamination.
有些人质疑我的决定
Some of the men questioned my judgment.
因为我要求他们和我一样
I was asking them to do what I had done.
牺牲他们的朋友
Sacrifice their friends...
他们的家人
their family.
他们当然拒绝了
Of course, they refused.
我只好把他们也杀了
So I had them killed too.
其他那些带着孩子的
Others with children...
被扔到了丛林里
deserted into the woods.
其中有个胆小鬼逃去找了北边我的上级
One of those cowards fled to my superiors up North.
他们试图说服我
They tried to convince me
说这场瘟疫可以用医疗手段解决
this plague could be dealt with medically.
那时我才意识到  他们根本没有
That's when I realized that they had learned nothing...
从过去中吸取教训
from our past.
你把他们也杀了
You killed them too?
我做了什么  普里彻
What did I do, Preacher?
你砍下了他们的头颅  长官
You severed their heads, sir.
除了我饶过的那个
Except for the one I spared...
好让他回去传个话
so that he could return, and deliver a message.
他们要是想夺我的权
If they wanted to relieve me of my command...
就得到我这来
they would have to meet me here...
自己来夺
and do it themselves.
这里原来是个武器库
This used to be a weapons depot.
危机刚开始的时候
They turned it into a relocation camp
他们把这变成了一个临时营地
when the crisis was just beginning.
但武器还在
But the weapons are still here...
在山里
inside the mountain.
会来多少人
How many men... will be coming?
可能全部都会来  别动什么歪脑筋
Probably all of them. But don't get any ideas.
比我更让他们害怕的  只有你们
The only thing they fear more than me is you apes.
这是一场...神圣的战争
This is... a holy war.
人类的全部历史导致了这一刻
All of human history has led to this moment.
如果我们输了
If we lose...
人类将会灭绝
we'll be the last of our kind.
这将成为一个人猿星球
It will be a planet of apes.
我们将会成为你们的牲口
And we will become your cattle.
看看你
Look at you.
你觉得我疯了  是吗
You think I'm sick, don't you?
我不是有意杀你儿子的
I didn't mean to kill your son.
但是如果他的命运注定是继承你的邪恶王国
But if his destiny was to inherit your unholy kingdom...
我很欣慰我杀了他
I'm glad I did it.
回来  蠢驴  摁住他
Get back! Donkey, hold him!
太感情用事了
So emotional!
我看得出你内心很挣扎
I can see how conflicted you are.
你分辨不清自己的意图
You're confused in your purpose.
你对我做的事感到愤怒
You are angry at me for something I did
可那是战争行为
that was an act of war.
但是你倾注太多个人情绪在里面了
But you're taking this all much too personally.
你觉得如果
What do you think...
你杀了我  我的人会怎么处置猿类
my men would have done to your apes if you had killed me?
还是对你而言杀了我更重要
Or is killing me more important?
到处都是士兵
Soldiers everywhere!
我们怎么进去
How will we get in?
无论如何得进去
Must get in somehow...
必须进去
Must get in!
进去  你说进去
In? In?
不行
No!
不能进  不行
No go in! No...
朋友  朋友
Friends, friends!
不  不能进
No, no go in.
不能进
No go in...
朋友  朋友
Friend! Friend!
谢谢你  朋友
Thank you, friend.
你救了我们的命
You saved our lives!
那些病人
Sick humans...
一定是从这下面逃走的
...must have escaped down here!
不  不  不
No! No! No!
别  别爬
No! No climb!
什么
What?
你看到什么了
What you see?
猿灾
现在
想知道我们在哪里吗
Wonder where we are?
不  朋友
Oh, no, friend!
不要
No!
不  不  不  回来  快回来
No! No! No! Come! Come!
回来  回来啊  回来
Come! Come back! Come!
不  快回来
No, come!
来  来  来
Come! Come! Come!
科巴
Koba!
睡吧
Sleep.
你救不了他们的
You cannot save them.
猿族将在这里灭族
Apes all die here.
不会的
No!
会的
Yes.
跟我走吧
Join me.
如果他明早还活着
If he's still alive in the morning...
就让他像他们一样干活去
he goes to work like everyone else...
或者你杀了他
or you shoot him.
过来  快过来
Come! Come, come.
她进去了
She go in!
渴吗
Thirsty...?
躲起来
Hide!
快
Quick!
人类会杀了她的
Humans will kill her!
我有办法  快走
I know what to do! Go!
举起手来
Arms up! Hey! Hey!
-举起手来  -当心  当心
- Arms up! - Watch it! Watch it!
我们走
Let's go!
跟上
Keep 'em up!
跟着他
Follow him down.
跟上他们
Keep them up!
外面有同伙吗
Are there others out there?
彻查区域
Sweep the area.
把他扔进围栏里
Put him in the pen.
感觉好点吗
Feeling better?
还好
Good.
接下来我们可以商量下
Then we can talk about...
逃跑的事
Escape.
猿族团结  则强
Apes together strong!
我们是开端
We are the beginning!
我们是结局
And the end!
还活着
Still alive.
把他送到采石场  单独去
Send him to the quarry. Alone.
等等
Hold on.
这是什么
What is this?
怎么会在笼子里
How did this get in there?
带他去做工
Get him to work.
三十七
Thirty-seven.
五十五
Fifty-five.
到成年监狱要三十七步
Thirty-seven steps to the adult cage...
到孩子们那里五十五步
Fifty-five to the children.
你要知道
You know...
等墙垒好
Colonel shoot apes...
上校会杀了猿族
when wall is done.
垒墙是负隅顽抗
His wall is madness.
救不了他的
It won't save him...
更救不了你
any more than it will save you.
我自己会救自己
I save myself.
你还有什么值得被救的
Is there anything left of you to save?
我挖的
I do.
猿族回笼子里了吗
Apes going back to the cage?
你
You...
很勇敢
Are very brave.
勇敢吗
Brave?
勇敢
Brave!
猿族
Ape?
我是吗
Me...?
猿族
Ape?
你是
You are...
诺娃
Nova.
来  来  过来看
Come! Come! Come see!
过来看
Come see!
来  过来看
Come! Come see!
34  35  36  37
34, 35, 36, 37...
37!
我挖的
I do.
现在怎么办
What now?
什么
What?
哦  不
Oh, no!
No, no!
不  不  不
No, no, no...
好吧
Okay.
这就是我跟你们说的那只猿
This is the ape I told you about!
谢谢你
Thank you.
坏猩猩
Bad Ape.
坏
Bad...
坏猩猩
Bad, Bad Ape.
坏
Bad...
怎么了
What's wrong?
我们不能再挖了
We can't keep digging!
隧道会被淹了的
It will flood the whole tunnel!
但如果不挖  就到不了孩子们那里
If we don't, we can't reach the children!
我们得持续关注下面动态
We must keep looking down there...
再想别的办法救孩子们
Find another way to reach the children....
现在我们必须离开
We must leave now!
会有更多的士兵赶来
More soldiers are coming!
人们将会互相残杀
Humans will destroy each other!
也会一并毁了我们
And us with them!
我们得从地面上把孩子们转移出去
We'll have to get the children out above ground!
怎么做...
How...?
你们这群畜生
You animals!
谁干的
Who did that?
是谁
Who was it?
是你吗
Was it you?
我爱你  儿子
I love you, son.
走  走  走
Go, go, go.
快  我们走
Hurry! Let's go!
凯撒  怎么了
Caesar, what's wrong?
快  你必须走
Hurry, you must go.
你不走吗
Without you?
不
No...
莫里斯说的对
Maurice was right.
我已经
I am...
科巴一样了
like Koba.
他没有摆脱
He could not...
他的仇恨
escape his hate.
我现在也无法摆脱我的
And I still cannot escape mine.
走  走  走
Go, go, go.
开火
Fire!
上校  上校
Colonel! Colonel!
他跑哪儿去了
Where the hell is he?
趴下  趴下  趴下
Down! Down! Down!
快趴下
Get down!
干掉他
Take him out!
快  蠢驴  我们上  装弹
Come on, donkey. Let's go! Reload!
上校  你在里面吗  上校
Colonel, are you in there? Colonel!
直接砸门
Just break it down.
蠢驴
Donkey!
枪榴弹发射器
Grenade launcher!
蠢驴  把发射器给我
God damn it, donkey! Get me the launcher!
不  不要
Oh, no! Oh, no!
别担心
Don't worry.
莫里斯
Maurice.
你们到家了
You are all home now.
猿族很强大
Apes are strong.
无论
With...
有没有我
or without me.
儿子
Son...
会知道
will know...
谁
who...
是
was...
父亲
father.
以及
And what...
凯撒
Caesar...
为我们
did...
做了什么
for us.
凯撒
Caesar...